# **CURRICULUM VITAE**

# Shailesh G. Jadhav

shailesh\_02@yahoo.co.in

: www.linkedin.com/in/shaileshjadhav

**!+91-9322133376 / 8369173759** 

## **Professional Summary:**



A self-administered and results-oriented Marketer with over 18 years of experience from B2B, B2C & Education sector relates to Packaging & Printing. A strategic professional with strong interpersonal, communication, problem solving and decision making skills. Having a rapt ability to identify business opportunities; provide management and technical expertise to sales representatives; maintain strong alliances; lead and motivate teams; conduct projects; exceed client expectations and achieve financial results.

## Work Experience:

### A. Academic Experience

## Visiting Faculty

(01 January 2016 - 30 December 2017)

Vertical Anchor - Gourang Paper Products Pvt. Ltd., Thane / Hub: IIGT-Thane

- One of the team member in developing the course curriculum and study notes for the vocational training in Printing and Packaging Technology.
- Visiting Faculty for B.Tech-Printing Technology course @ TISS-SVE.
- Conducted few special topic lectures for the students of vocational training.

# Visiting Faculty

(03 September 2016 - 15 November 2016)

PRUT, Saket Institute of Management, Kalyan

Visiting Faculty for Subject-Marketing Management at MMS Course 1<sup>st</sup> Year.

Asst. Professor

(01 July 2009 - 30 April 2014)

Dept. of Printing & Packaging Tech.

### SIES Graduate School of Technology, Navi Mumbai

- Started as a lecturer and raised to Asst. Professor in the department, Handled the responsibility of Head of the department between June 2011 to June 2013.
- Managing the day to day activity, controlling and coordinating the faculty responsibility,
  Arranging the faculty development programs, generating funds, managing the quarterly
  wall magazine. Key member in successful installation of the printing press, Design
  software in the department.
- Arranging the Industrial visit for students and taking care of placements for the department. Successfully organized the department 1<sup>st</sup> International Conference titled Biopack-2013.

## B. Industrial Experience

# Sales Associate (Freelancer)

(01July 2018 - Till this date)

## **Project-2**

- Working as a Sales Associate for a company that manufactures compostable and biodegradable raw materials use as an alternative to replace single use plastics.
- Developed the new customers from plastic processing industries.
- Guiding the customers to complete CPCB registration and CIPET testing.
- Based on the customers product needs, suggesting the use of different raw materials combination, supporting in troubleshooting while processing the raw materials.
- Design and develop a company monthly newsletter, promoting the products through various leading exhibitions in India.

# Sales Associate (Freelancer)

(01Aug. 2015 - 30 June 2018)

# Project-1

- Worked as a Sales Associate for Paperbag manufacturing Company based in Thane.
- Successfully developed the new customers from construction, garment industry.
- Generating the leads for paper bags, understand the customer needs and suggest the appropriate paper or paperboards. Preparing the estimates.

# Asst. Manager-Marketing-Packaging Print House India Pvt. Ltd, Navi Mumbai

(15 July 2014 - 10 June 2015)

- Successfully developed the new customers from Industrial and Food Company.
- Generated new leads for mono cartons from food segment, plus managing the existing clients from Pharma Company. Preparing the estimates.

### **Business Consultant – Partner**

(01 Sept.2008 - 30 June 2009)

# Magic Box, Mumbai

- This was a partnership gifting venture, marketing and selling crystals engraved with laser using patented Canadian technology.
- Consulted the company from Pune in setting up a tea as well as oil fried products
  packing unit. Job involves packaging development of the cartons, laminate structures,
  documentation and approvals from FDA, new vendor development for VFFS machines,
  coding machines, packaging material suppliers, and laboratory equipment, develop the
  in-house quality control laboratory. Scheduling the production plan as per the marketing
  requirements. Supporting the marketing team in product promotion.

#### Sales Officer

(13 March 2007 - 31Aug. 2008)

## Thomson Press, Mumbai

- Successfully developed the new clients' base for brochure, dairies, in-house magazine, and annual reports.
- Managing the existing clients and preparing the print estimates.

# **Business Development Executive** Kris Flexipacks Pvt. Ltd., Mumbai

- Started as a Packaging development officer for shrink sleeve division- job involves developing the sample sleeves, key line diagram, arranging the sample sleeves for customer's trial run, Troubleshooting on Sleeving, Promotion through exhibitions. Part of a team member in developing the innovative sleeves for Indian and International companies.
- In second year promoted to Packaging development and coordinator for the poly bag division, the job was to develop new poly bag types for the Indian market, Find the various suppliers for the development of the machine according to the design of the poly bag, Trial run of the machine.
- In third year promoted to Business Development Executive for their newly established Flexible Packaging division, generated lead and maintaining customer relationships from food and Pharma segments. Developing the samples as per the customer's requirement for approval, arranging the sample roll for customers' trial, preparing the estimate for print laminates.

## Printing Supervisor – Flexo Dept.

(30 March 2001- 28 April 2003)

## **Huhtamaki India Ltd. Formerly PPL, Thane**

- Hands-on experience of operating a Canadian label press with inline UV coating, hot stamping, cutting, slitting and sheet operations, etc.
- Setting up the press, make ready for printing, Label productions as per the schedule, preparing the ink shades, indenting the raw materials from store, troubleshooting on press for quality output, machine maintenance etc.
- Perform the Q.C check on the labels using Inspection cum Slitting machine.

### Education:

- Ph.D. Marketing Management Pursuing from SPPU, since February 2021.
- M.B.A Marketing Management 57.92%, SPPU, July 2006.
- **B.E Printing Technology 67.46%,** SPPU, August 2000.
- HSC Science 60.00%, Mumbai Board, March 1994.
- **SSC 63.57%,** Mumbai Board, March 1992.

### Training and Certifications:

- Completed three-day interactive program on Certified Trainer in Package Testing at SIES School of Packaging, Nerul.
- Attended training course on ISO 17025:2005 on Laboratory Management System and Internal Audit at IRMRA, Thane.

### Additional Information:

Address: Shree-Nalini, Flat No-003, Basement, Vadavali Section, Ambernath-East,

District-Thane-421501

Date of Birth: 2<sup>nd</sup> December1976

Marital Status: Unmarried

Language known: English, Marathi, Hindi.

# **Hobbies-activities & interests:**

Like to know people, Music, Trekking, Reading, Pro-bono Consulting and have written article on Packaging in magazine like Adviteeya, Food and Beverages News, Ingredient South Asia, Chronicle Pharmabiz etc.